Losing the past was very costly.
（観察者）失った過去の代償は
非常に大きなものとなった
March's agility,
マーチの敏捷(びんしょう)さ オニグマの力
Oniguma's might,
Gugu's fire-breathing...
グーグーの火炎放射
Unable to make use of any of those things,
その いずれも使えないフシは
Fushi struggled in his fight
against the returning Nokkers.
再び出現したノッカーを相手に
苦戦する
But the people of Jananda
Island came to his aid.
だがジャナンダ島(とう)の者たちが
彼を助けた
The Nokkers were defeated,
and Fushi reclaimed his past.
ノッカーは倒され
フシは過去を取り戻した
This island may be the school at which Fushi
will be guided in his growth as a person.
この島は
フシを人としての成熟へ導く
学び舎なのかもしれない
♪～
～♪
The Children's Dreams
Well, let's celebrate our victory!
（トナリ）では我々の勝利を祝して
Cheers!
かんぱーい！
（一同）かんぱーい！
Drink this, Mister Immortal.
（ウーパ）不死身さん
これ飲みなさい 牛の血
Cow blood.
（フシ）ん？
Seconds?
（フシ）お代わり？
（ウーパ）うん
Yeah.
So, tell us the rest of your story.
（ウーロイ）で さっきの話の
続きを聞かせてくれよ
About what the man in black said.
（ミァ）黒い男が言ってたこと
Right.
ああ…
When I transform, it's into a person
or animal I've met before who died.
変身したオレの姿ってのは
オレが今まで出会って
死んだ人や動物たちで
He says the Nokkers are here to
take those forms away from me.
その姿を奪いに来たのが
ノッカーらしい
The reason it looked the way it did
さっきのやつが
あんな形をしてたのは
was because it had taken the
form of the bear away from me.
オレからクマの姿を
奪ったからなんだ
Wait, you're saying you can
transform into a bear?
じゃあ あんた
クマの姿にもなれるの？
Yeah.
Wow!
（フシ）うん
（サンデル）すげえ！
Then can't you defeat the Nokkers
by transforming into one of them?
ていうか
ノッカーの姿になって
ノッカーを倒せば よくない？
I'm a genius!
私 天才！
I haven't tried that before.
それは試したことないや
But the Nokkers aren't quite
what you think they are.
でもノッカーは
みんなに感じるのとは違うんだ
Like, they're not really... things.
何もないっていうか…
And are you being controlled
by that asshole in black?
（ナンド）それで あんたは その
イヤな黒いヤツの
言いなりになってるのか？
I'm just doing as he says because
I don't want to f-forget people.
みんなのことを忘れたくないから
言うとおりにしてるだけ
Hey, don't you have any
dreams for the future?
ねえ あなたは将来の夢はないの？
Dreams?
Yeah. Things you want to do.
夢？
そう 自分がやりたいこと
ん… １人でノッカーを
倒せるようになりたいかな
I want to be able to defeat the
Nokkers by myself, I guess.
Weird.
ヘンなの
No, it's super cool!
カッコいいですよ
I don't mean like that.
そういうのじゃなくて
もっと普通の ないの？
How about something more ordinary?
My dream is to become a
model for a famous artist.
私の夢はね
有名な絵描きの
モデルになることなの
I think there's a lot that I don't know yet.
オレは たぶん
まだ知らないことが多いんだ
Something might change if I leave
here and learn more things.
だから ここを出て もっと
いろいろ知ったら何か変わるかも…
That's true.
そうね
Our dream right now is to leave this island.
私たちの夢は
まず この島を出ること
Once we do, we're going to find a place
that suits us, and live our lives.
出たら 俺らに合った土地を探して
好きにやるんだ！
I want a ton of animals!
俺は たくさん動物を飼いたいな
I want to become a doctor.
僕は医者になりたいです
My dream's already been granted.
私の夢は もう かなったよ
What was your dream, again?
何でしたっけ？
I've always wanted to know
where the sun comes from.
（ウーパ）太陽が どこから
来るのか ずっと知りたかった
It comes from the ocean.
海から来るんだね
Oopa was born on this island.
She doesn't know about the outside world.
ウーパは この島で生まれたから
外の世界を知らないの
What about your dream, Tonari?
トナリの夢は？
Mine?
ん？　あたし？
My dream is...
あたしの夢は…
to surprise my dad.
お父さんをビックリさせることだよ
Say what?
何だ それ？
お父さん 死んでるんだろ？
I thought you said your dad's dead.
You're going to leave the island
and become a writer, right?
島を出て 作家になるのよね？
Yo, Tonari, the final is
starting tomorrow at noon.
（班長）よお トナリ！
決勝戦は明日の昼からだってよ
And about procuring a ship...
それと船の手配だが
Captain Skyfish is no good.
スカイフィッシュ船長
ありゃダメだ
I just can't convince him to do it.
全然 首を縦に振ってくれねえ
I'm not surprised.
だろうね
What, you can't use the ship?
何？　船 使えないの？
It would work out if you helped.
あんたが手伝ってくれれば
うまくいくさ
All right, let's eat!
さあ 食おう！
We need you in good shape for the final.
決勝戦に向けて
精をつけてもらわなきゃな
（ウーパ･サンデル･ウーロイ）
えー！　これだけ？
This is it?!
Don't complain.
ぜいたく言わない
（一同）ええっ
Eat up.
好きなだけ食べて
わあ！
Oh, man!
すげえ！
This came out of your body, didn't it?!
うえっ これ
あんたの体から出したんだろ？
Try it, Tonari!
トナリも食べてみなよ
おいしいよ！
It's delicious!
ええ… うへっ
（食べる音）
Yum!
（トナリ）おいしい！
（ウーロイ）なっ！
（倒れる音）
（一同の寝息）
Guys...
みんな… どうしたの？
What's wrong?
あっ
The western morning glory
is indeed effective.
（ハヤセ）ニシアサガオは
よく効きますね
（リガードの鳴き声）
Sorry, I didn't realize.
ごめん 気がつかなかったんだ
"I'm finally going to ask
him to eat with us today."
（フシ）“今日こそ
あの人を食事に誘おう”
I want to bring everyone joy,
because they brought me joy.
（トナリ）私を幸せにしてくれた
みんなのために
みんなを幸せにしたい
（トナリ）んん… ハッ
Sorry...
ごめん
for bringing you here.
ここに連れてきて
Yeah.
うん
ん？
This is my story.
（トナリ）これは私の物語
Hey, Ligard, what's your dream?
（トナリ）ねえ リガード
あなたの夢って何？
My dream is to surprise Dad.
あたしの夢はね
パパをビックリさせること！
"What's this? What is this book?"
“おや 何だ この本は！
とんでもなく おもしろいぞ”
"It's very interesting!"
"Who wrote it?"
“一体 誰が書いたんだ！”
“むむむ… 俺の娘か！”
"It must have been my daughter!"
Like that.
Dad's home.
…ってね
（トナリの母）パパが帰ってきたわ
I was seven years old.
（トナリ）私は７歳だった
Welcome home, honey.
お疲れさま あなた
Welcome home, Dad!
おかえり パパ！
I'm home, Tonari.
（トナリの父）ただいま トナリ
According to one book, a person's fate
remains in God's hands until they turn seven.
（トナリ）ある本によれば
人間は７歳までは
神に運命を握られているらしい
It was a chilly day.
その日は寒い日だった
（あくび）
えっ！
When I woke up, my mother was dead.
（トナリ）
朝 起きると母が死んでいた
The Church decided that my
father was the murderer.
教会は父が犯人だと判断した
In my land, murderers
are sent to the island.
この地域では
殺人犯は島流しにされる
I was met with a dilemma: do I
stay here and live as an orphan,
私は決断を迫られた
ここに残って孤児として暮らすか
or do I leave for the island with my father?
父と共に島送りにされるか
I decided to follow my father.
私は父に ついていくことにした
I believed in him.
なぜなら信じていたから
My father wasn't the murderer.
父は やってないって
Awaiting me was a world of people
who'd given up on being people.
私を待ち受けていたのは
人間をやめた者たちの
住む世界だった
The island, made up of murderers and their
families, had its own distinct culture.
殺人犯と その家族で
構成された島には
独自の文化があった
People were granted freedom of all kinds.
ありとあらゆる自由が
認められていたのだ
All kinds...
ありとあらゆる…
Including murder.
つまり殺人も
There was no organization that
would crack down on them.
それを取り締まる組織はなかった
Of course, there were good people, too.
もちろん善良な人はいたが…
Most people were obsessed with
ほとんどの島民は
the tournament to determine
the leader of the island.
島のリーダーを決める
闘技場での大会に熱中していた
（男性）ぐはっ
（歓声）
But it didn't take me long to understand:
（トナリ）だが すぐに分かった
These people aren't looking for a leader.
みんな リーダーを
欲しているのではない
They're just satisfying
their lust for control.
支配したい欲求を
満たしているのだと…
I plan on entering the tournament.
（トナリの父）
あの大会に出ようと思うんだ
What? Please don't, Dad!
えっ やめてよ パパ！
I heard that some people
won in the tournament,
あれに優勝して島長になり
became the island leader, and left.
その権限で島を出たヤツが
過去にいたらしい
But it's too dangerous.
でも あんな危険な大会…
I'm aware that it's dangerous.
危険は承知のうえだ
We can't leave on our own accord.
自力で脱出しようにも
All the islanders are keeping
an eye on each other.
ここでは島民全員が
監視し合ってる
It's safer to leave officially.
だったら堂々と出たほうが安全だ
I'm sorry for what you've had to go through.
俺 お前に申し訳なくてな
You must hate it here.
こんな所 イヤだろう？
But...
だけど…
Those people look like they're
having so much fun killing people.
あの人たち みんな
楽しそうに人を殺して…
From now on, it'll be too
dangerous for you to be near me.
これからは
俺と一緒にいると危険だ
We'll meet up at the port at Ipo
once the tournament is over.
大会が終わったら
イーポの船着き場で会おう
Don't worry.
安心しろ！　俺は死なない
I'm not going to die.
（大歓声）
（トナリの父の雄たけび）
I prayed to God...
（トナリ）私は神に祈った
for my father to be the last one standing.
最後まで立っているのが
父でありますようにと
（男性）ぐはっ
（男性）うっ
（トナリの父の荒い息）
フハハハ…
My father wasn't standing there.
（トナリ）
そこに… 父は立っていなかった
Is that it for the first round?
（島民）
初戦のヤツらは これで全部だな
There's going to be more coming.
（島民）これから また増えるぞ
Dad?
（トナリ）どこ… パパどこ？
Where are you, Dad?
Where are you?
どこ？
どこ…
（鳥の鳴き声）
（大歓声）
（リガードの鳴き声）
I haven't found him yet.
まだ見つかってないよ
ちょっと待ってな
Hold on.
The new leader is going to be great.
（島民）
今度の島長は期待できるな
Yeah, he was strong.
（島民）ああ 強かった
エラン･ジー･ダルトンだっけ？
Elan G. Dalton, was it?
（リガードの鳴き声）
あ…
Happy birthday.
（トナリの父）“誕生日おめでとう
この本で お前の夢をつむげ”
Write your dreams in this book.
Your father, Elan G. Dalton.
“お前の父
エラン･ジー･ダルトンより”
（トナリの父）ぐはっ
I'm sorry, Tona...ri.
す… すまない
トナ… リ…
He's dead.
（島民）死んだぞ 毒が効いた
The poison worked.
That's for Cleff!
（島民）
クレフの仇(かたき)だ ざまあみろ！
Serves you right!
What do we do with him?
（島民）こいつ どうする？
Throw him in the water.
（島民）海に捨てよう
One, two...
（島民）せーの…
（島民たち）それ！
The day I turned eight,
I decided to begin my own story.
（トナリ）８歳になった その日
私は私で物語を始めようと思った
Why are you crying?
（ミァ）なんで泣いてるの？
Age nine.
（トナリ）９歳… 居場所ができた
I have a place to call home.
There were more children who were
in the same situation as me.
私と同じような境遇の子供が
ここにはいた
What do you want to do when
you leave this place?
（トナリ）いつか ここを出たら
みんな何がしたい？
Age ten.
（トナリ）
10歳… みんなで夢を語り合った
We discussed our dreams together.
I smiled for the first
time since I came here.
ここに来て初めて ちゃんと笑った
Age eleven.
11歳… 脱出計画を練り始める
We begin plotting our escape.
Age twelve.
12歳… 仕入れの仕事に就く
I take on import work.
It's the one opportunity to leave the island.
唯一 島の外へ出られる機会
I'd hoped it would be our means of
escape, but the sailors are watchful.
脱出の手段としたいが
船員の監視は厳しい
Ow!
イダッ
Get the hell out of here!
（街の男）さっさと立ち去れ！
Criminals don't belong here!
罪人が こんな所
うろつくんじゃねえ！
Age thirteen.
（トナリ）13歳…
I realize that outsiders aren't open to us.
外の人が私たちに
寛容でないことを実感する
For a moment, I lost sight of myself.
一瞬 自分が分からなくなった
Age fourteen.
（トナリ）14歳… 彼に出会う
I meet him.
So white.
真っ白…
Place him on the ship.
（女）
あの少年を船に乗せなさい
He will surely win.
彼は必ず優勝するわ
And he will become a legend.
そして伝説になる
He'll upturn everything,
すべてをひっくり返すの
ジャナンダも⸺
including Jananda and your fate.
あなたの運命も
Guide him.
あなたが導きなさい
She was a visitor.
（トナリ）その人は客人だった
I'd heard that people would sometimes
come to watch the tournament
闘技場の大会を見学して
気に入った島民を買う人が
時々 島を訪れるという
and buy people that they liked.
What she said was true.
（トナリ）
その人の言葉は本当だった
As soon as he came to the island,
everyone on it was captivated.
島に来て すぐ
彼は みんなを虜(とりこ)にした
He was immortal.
彼は不死身だった！
They say that in every story,
there's a turning point.
どの物語にも
転換点というものがあるという
This might be that moment.
今が そのときなのかもしれない
No.
（トナリ）いや…
It must be.
きっと そうだ！
（リガードの鳴き声）
（フシ）ふっ んん…
Pioran!
ピオラン！
（ピオラン）うっ
Fushi?
フシ？
You fool. I'm so glad you came.
たわけ… よう来たのう
I can get you out of here soon, Pioran.
ピオラン もうすぐ
出してあげられるよ
But this room is locked from outside.
しかし ここは外から
鍵で閉じられとる
One swipe from Oniguma, and we're out.
あんなの オニグマで一撃さ
The final round of the island
leader tournament is tomorrow.
明日 シマオサ決定戦の
決勝があるんだ
Once I win, we can prepare a ship.
優勝したら船を用意できる
We can leave with our heads held high.
堂々と出ていこう
Fushi...
フシ… たくましくなったのう
You've become so reliable.
（リガードの鳴き声）
Ligard's calling.
リガードが呼んでる もう行くね
I'd better go.
Listen...
ええか 無理はするなよ
Don't put yourself in any danger.
I'm not.
してないよ
Bye.
（フシ）じゃ…
The time has come at last for the final round!
（実況の男）ついに
やってまいりました 決勝戦！
This battle will determine the
next leader of the island!
この戦いで
次の島長が決定いたします
Immortal, give me your hand.
不死身 手出して
If you have a hard time knocking
them unconscious, use this.
相手を気絶させるのに手こずったら
これを使うといい
It's Oopa's blowgun.
ウーパの吹き矢だ
Thanks.
ありがとう
S-Sure.
あ… うん
I thought you might not come.
来てくれないかと思ってたから…
よかったよ
I'm glad.
Don't worry.
大丈夫 勝って
みんなを外へ連れていく
I'll win and take everyone outside.
Please welcome our contestants!
（実況の男）選手入場！
（大歓声）
It's been a while,
（女）久しぶりですね
Fushi.
フシ
Poor little March, huh?
マーチ…
かわいそうな少女でしたね
With her dreams and hopes
夢も希望も…
being cut short.
（ハヤセ）断ち切られて
ハッ
March...
（フシ）マーチ
（うめき声）
You killed her.
（フシ）お前が殺した
You...
お前が…
Ah.
（ハヤセ）ああ…
そうでしたね
That's right, I did.
Don't worry about her.
案ずることはありません
Death brings freedom.
死は自由をもたらしてくれる
A bear!
（観客）おお クマだ！
（観客）やっちまえ！
Go, Mister Immortal!
不死身さん がんばれ！
Is something the matter, Fushi?
（ハヤセ）
どうかしましたか フシ？
（フシのうめき声）
Tear my chest apart,
like you did last time.
あのときみたいに
私を胸から えぐってくださいよ
（うめき声）
That wasn't satisfying.
（ハヤセ）物足りないですね
I don't think you can so much
as touch me in that body.
その体では私に触れることさえ
できないのでは？
Why are you here?
（フシ）何をしに来た？
死にに来たのか？
Did you come to die?
What's your purpose here?
何のために ここに？
I don't like this feeling.
なんかヤな感じだな
Well?
どうです その女の乗り心地は？
How does it feel controlling that woman?
（フシ）え？
She's so light and soft and nimble, isn't she?
（ハヤセ）軽くて…
柔らかくて…
よく動くでしょう？
She's my gift to you.
私からの贈り物です
（フシ）あ…
（雷鳴）
I wasn't sure how I should kill her.
（ハヤセ）
どこを狙うべきか迷いましたが
I would have felt bad cutting her stomach...
おなかは かわいそうなので
So I decided on her face.
顔にしました
But that wasn't easy, either.
しかし それも
なかなか手こずりましてね
So I had to take her throat.
仕方なく首を狙ってあげました
How pathetic of me.
我ながら情けない
I couldn't finish her in a single blow.
一撃でしとめられないなんて…
Because of that, she suffered
more than she needed to.
（ハヤセ）そのせいで
ムダに苦しませてしまいました
（観客のヤジ）
You killed Parona?
（フシ）あんたが…
パロナを殺したのか？
Isn't that what I just said?
今 そう言いましたが？
I'll kill you!
殺してやる！
えっ？
フフ…
（フシ）うりゃあ！
You cannot
（ハヤセ）これでは…
defeat me like this.
私ひとり倒せないですね
You may be immortal, but you're feeble.
（フシ）わああ…
（ハヤセ）あなたは…
不死身というだけで…
とても か弱い
（フシ）あ…
The western morning glory is quite potent.
ニシアサガオは よく効く
（フシ）ああ…
（どよめき）
（大歓声）
The immortal freak is incapacitated!
（実況の男）
不死身の怪物が戦闘不能！
We have a winner!
優勝者が決定しました
新しい島長の誕生です！
It's the birth of a new island leader!
Immortal...
不死身…
♪～
～♪
Preview
An unexpected proposal from their
newly crowned leader, Hayase,
（観察者）島長となったハヤセの
思いがけない提案に
stirs up the people of Jananda.
ジャナンダの民は ざわめく
She captures Fushi and plots
to make him her own thing.
フシを捕え わがものにしようと
たくらむハヤセ
Tonari fights back viciously.
懸命に抗(あらが)うトナリ
She, too, is pushed forward
by her feelings for Fushi.
トナリもまた フシへの思いに
突き動かされてゆく
The Defeated